

Tel: (+46) 76 779 0234

Email: <a href="mailto:abbashayder@hotmail.com">abbashayder@hotmail.com</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/abbas-hayder">linkedin.com/in/abbas-hayder</a>
GitHub: <a href="mailto:https://github.com/Aquabbas">https://github.com/Aquabbas</a>
Website: <a href="https://aquabbas.github.io">https://aquabbas.github.io</a>



### **Profile**

Results-driven software engineer with 1+ years of experience in system development, customer support, with an ability to break down complex problems and solve them iteratively. Familiar with various programming languages and frameworks. Aspiring towards becoming a valuable tech lead.

### **Skills**

**Programming Languages:** TypeScript | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | Python | C++.

**Libraries & Frameworks:** React.js | Three.js | FastAPI.

**Tools:** Node.js | Vite | WebGL | Blender | Git | GitHub Actions | Trello | Jira.

Databases: MongoDB | SQLite | PostgreSQL.

**Platforms:** GitHub | Vercel | Render | AWS | Azure.

**Soft Skills:** Problem Solving, Communication, Adaptability, Customer Focus.

## **Education**

Mid Sweden University, Sundsvall, Sweden — B.Sc. Computer Engineering, 2022.

# **Work Experience**

### **Creative Developer [Internship]**

https://aquabbas.github.io — Stockholm, Sweden — Nov, 2023 — Current

- Learning Three.js & developing immersive web applications:
  - Current GitHub Repository
  - Personal Website & Blog
- Working on acquiring a Three.js certification from Three.js Journey.

### **System Developer [Full-Time]**

Knowit Solutions Cocreate — Göteborg, Sweden — Aug, 2022 — Feb, 2023

- Implemented a TypeScript-based bot for occupancy queries in Microsoft Teams.
- Established GitHub workflows for Docker container deployment to Microsoft Azure.

#### IT Support [Part-Time]

Mid Sweden University — Sundsvall, Sweden — Sep, 2019 — Jun, 2021

- Performed comprehensive inspections of operating system (OS), application, and network issues.
- Executed system maintenance/updates for Mac-, Windows- and Linux-OS.